Guide to the Church of the Ascension, Pittsburgh, Pa. Records, 1889-1996 AIS.1996.02
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Church of the Ascension, Pittsburgh, Pa. Records
1889-1996
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Church of the Ascension (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
AIS.1996.02
3 microfilm_reels
The collection consists of three reels of microfilm containing the family, baptismal, marriage, and burial records of the Church of The Ascension, a parish of the Episcopal Diocese of Pittsburgh located in Shadyside at 4729 Ellsworth Avenue.
History
The Church of The Ascension, a parish of the Episcopal Diocese of Pittsburgh, was originally formed in 1887 by a group of Episcopalians seeking a place of worship close to their homes. In 1889 the group built a small wooden church on a vacant Ellsworth Avenue lot. The space soon proved to be inadequate and in 1897 construction began on the present church structure. Located in Shadyside at 4729 Ellsworth Avenue, the Church of The Ascension continues to remain active and involved in the Pittsburgh community.
Scope and Content Notes
The collection includes thirteen volumes of microfilmed church records organized into two series. Series I includes volumes 1-10 and contains information of church records of indexes, families, baptisms, confirmations, burials, marriages, pastors, rectors, and assistant ministers dated 1889-1996. Series II includes volumes 11-13 and contains information of church logbook entries, deeds, meeting minutes, and church finances dated 1905-1925.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Microfilmed by the Archives Service Center with permission from the Church of the Ascension, Pittsburgh, Pa., 1996.
Previous Citation
Church of the Ascension, Pittsburgh, Pa. Records, 1889-1996, AIS.1996.02, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Church records and registers -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Churches and Synagogues; Shadyside (Pittsburgh, Pa.); Episcopal Church -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Church of the Ascension (Pittsburgh, Pa.); Episcopal Church. Diocese of Pittsburgh
- Church Congregation Records, 1889-1996; I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  Series I includes ten volumes of microfilmed records of the Church of the Ascension dated 1889-1996. These volumes contain information of indexes, families, baptisms, confirmations, burials, marriages, pastors, rectors, and assistant ministers.
  - Volume 1 (Microfilm-cabinet 3, Drawer 7, Reel 1)
    - Index of Names
    - Families
    - Baptisms
    - Confirmed
    - Burials, 1907-1909
    - Marriages, 1889-1906
    - Burials, 1889-1906
  - Volume 2 (Microfilm-cabinet 3, Drawer 7, Reel 2)
    - Baptisms
    - Confirmed, 1912-1915
    - Marriages
    - Burials
    - Index of Names
  - Volume 3 (Microfilm-cabinet 3, Drawer 7, Reel 2)
    - Rectors, 1915
    - Assistant Ministers, 1916-1918
    - Communicants
    - Baptisms
    - Confirmations
    - Burials
    - Appendix of List of Families
  - Volume 4 (Microfilm-cabinet 3, Drawer 7, Reel 2)
    - Index of Names
    - Rectors
    - Assistant Ministers
    - Communicants
    - Baptisms
    - Confirmations
    - Burials, 1915-1942
  - Volume 5 (Microfilm-cabinet 3, Drawer 7, Reel 2)
    - Communicants, 1943-1954
    - Baptisms, 1942-1995
    - Confirmations, 1942-1992
    - Burials, 1942-1996
  - Volume 6 (Microfilm-cabinet 3, Drawer 7, Reel 2)
    - Index of Names
    - Marriages, 1905-1912
  - Volume 7 (Microfilm-cabinet 3, Drawer 7, Reel 2)
    - Index of Names
    - Marriages, 1915-1945
  - Volume 8 (Microfilm-cabinet 3, Drawer 7, Reel 3)
    - Index of Names
    - Marriages, 1946-1985
  - Volume 9 (Microfilm-cabinet 3, Drawer 7, Reel 3)
    - Marriages, 1986-1996
  - Volume 10 (Microfilm-cabinet 3, Drawer 7, Reel 3)
    - Confirmations
- Church Records of Internal Affairs, 1905-1924; II.
  Series II includes three volumes of microfilmed records related to the internal affairs of the Church of the Ascension dated 1905-1924. These volumes contain logbook entries, meeting minutes, statements of receipts, deed information, and miscellaneous notes. It should be noted that portions of the records of volume 11 have faded and are illegible.
  - Volume 11 (Microfilm-cabinet 3, Drawer 7, Reel 3)
    - Notes, Logbook Entries, Deed Information, Meeting Minutes
  - Volume 12 (Microfilm-cabinet 3, Drawer 7, Reel 3)
    - Meeting Minutes, 1905-1915
  - Volume 13 (Microfilm-cabinet 3, Drawer 7, Reel 3)
    - Meeting Minutes
    - Statement of Receipts, 1921-1924